In this video, I'm going to just
demonstrate some of the other formatting
and structural tools that you can
use to create your presentation.
As you can see for this presentation
I created this from a new blank
presentation, which primarily gives
me full control over the layout
and design of each of the slides.
I start with a white background, and then
I then have to decide what the layout
of the slide will be, how it will be
structured, what text would be used, what
font, what size, how it would be coloured.
And I have full control over that.
Alternatively, you can select
a preformatted template.
So if I went to File and obviously I've
got the option for a blank presentation,
or then I can select more themes.
And then that gives me a
wide range of templates and
themes that I can select from.
I could pick any one of those and then
straight away, I've got a formatting
option everything's been applied.
I would then just need to
populate the actual presentation.
So if I click on that one
there and select create.
One of the issues here is the file
size, it's very big and that will be
because of the quality of the images
and the resolution of the images.
So if you're constrained by file size,
you may find that you need to be careful
on the type of presentation or the
type of template that you're using.
So as you can see, this has already
been formatted in a certain way.
And if I click on new slide and I select
another title slide two content slide.
As you can see, there are
various formatting elements
that have already been applied.
So if I just actually closed
that one down and go back to the
original presentation, as I say I
have full control over this one.
So if I was following a house style,
this would be more appropriate because
then I could apply the various formatting
and design that needs to be applied
following the company guidelines.
When working with your presentation, you
still have the option to apply a variety
of themes or design styles to that.
If I go to the design tab, as you can see,
I have a range of themes along the top.
So if I just move my cursor along
each theme, so that's the theme I'm
using at the moment, which is office
theme, which is the default theme
I can then move it further along.
And I have facet theme,
gallery theme, integral theme.
And as you can see, it makes changes.
So it's giving you an example of what
your presentation will look like if you
select that theme again, there are a wide
range of themes that you may wish to use.
So at the moment, I'm just sticking
with the one that was the original one.
You also have variants of the themes.
So, the colours can be changed.
All the different as you can see , when
I move my cursor down through these,
it's changing the various effects.
So I can select a variety of
different features and different
tools to apply to the slide.
You also have the design idea.
So very similar to the templates.
If I click on the design ideas, it
looks at the presentation and then
it generates ideas based around that.
So as you can see, it is
looking at various ways of
structuring the information.
So if I decided that I wanted to
go with one of those, all I would
do would be to click on that.
And then that would change the layout
and structure of the slide to fit.
I'll just close that
down and I'll undo that.
So that's covering the
themes, designs and styles.
As I say, some of the most popular,
ones are quite straightforward
and that will apply that to every
slide within the presentation.
As you can see, you would then need to
go back in because the text there isn't
working it should be black text again.
So I'd have to go back in and change
that and change the colour of the text.
Again, the chart is going
over the border into there.
So as you can see, there are elements
that you would still need to go in and
change, but if you are happy with the
actual design theme, you would then
just be able to work with that and
make the changes that you needed to.
So I'm just going to undo adding that.
So I'm back to my plain for
slide presentation that I've
applied my own formatting to.
It may be a case that all I need
to do is I'm happy with having just
plain white slides but maybe add a
slightly different background colour.
So again, just go to the design tab
and look at the format background.
So if I click on that it will
allow me to select a range of
options so I can have a solid fill.
Then I can pick a colour.
And so I could go for perhaps that
colour that will automatically apply
that, but it only applies that to that
slide I'd need to select, apply to
all to make sure that it would select
that and apply it to all the slides.
So if I do that now, as you
can see, each of the slides now
has that colour applied to it.
I'm just going to undo that and undo that.
So again, I can look
through all the colours.
Is there anything else more appropriate?
I could also have what's
called a gradient fill.
Which applies some form of
shading gradient to the colour.
So it goes from white to blue and you can
play around with the preset gradients,
you can have linear, rectangular so a
variety of tools that you can mess about
with have a look, see what you like
again, do I apply that to all slides?
Does that look good?
I'm quite happy with that.
Yep.
That's great.
I can also have a picture or texture
infills so I could have a picture applied.
Now I have a picture set up as
default, so it's actually applied
that as the background there.
So I'll just undo do that and
go back to the gradient fill.
So I'm quite happy with that or a
pattern fill again, you would select
the pattern that you wish and...
but I'm quite happy with the gradient
fill because I think with it being
a presentation about balloon rides
the blue and the sky looks OK.
So once you're happy with the the
background of the presentation,
I can close that down, and again,
it's more about just adding
some structure and definition to
each of the individual slides.
So I go back to the home tab again, I'm
going to go and select a black border
for that and a black border for that.
And the infill I will use again,
I'm just going to stick with the
one that I selected originally.
And again, for this one border around
that border, around that, do the infill.
At the moment, I'm quite happy
with the layout and the design
that I've applied to that.